(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-09-19T13:02:43.785809",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
せーのっ
Ready, set—
でもそんなんじゃだめ もうそんなんじゃほら
But that's just no good, hey, that's just not enough, look!
心は進化するよ もっともっと
My heart keeps evolving, more and more!
言葉にすれば消えちゃう関係なら
If words would just make our connection vanish,
言葉を消せばいいやって思ってた 恐れてた
I thought, "Well, I can just erase the words," and I was so afraid.
だけどあれ? なんか違うかも
But wait, maybe something's different?
千里の道も一歩から
Even a journey of a thousand miles starts with a single step.
石のように固いそんな意思で
With a resolve as hard as stone,
塵も積もれば大和撫子?
Even dust piled up makes a traditional Japanese beauty?
死ぬ気で いや死ぬ気で
With all my might, no, like my life depends on it!
ふわふわり ふわふわ る
Float, floating, floating away—
あなたが名前を呼ぶ それだけで宙へ浮く
Just by you calling my name, I float up into the sky!
ふわふわる ふわふわり
Floating, floating, floating away—
あなたが笑っている それだけで笑顔になる
Just by you smiling, it makes me smile too!
神様ありがとう 運命のいたずらでも
Thank you, God, even if it's just fate playing tricks,
めぐり逢えたことが 幸せなの
The fact that we were able to meet makes me so happy.
でもそんなんじゃだめ もうそんなんじゃほら
But that's just no good, hey, that's just not enough, look!
心は進化するよ もっともっと
My heart keeps evolving, more and more!
そうそんなんじゃいやだ もうそんなんじゃまだ
That's right, I hate that, no, that's still not enough,
私のこと見ててね ずっとずっと
Keep looking at me, always and forever!
恋愛サーキュレーション
Renai Circulation
私の中のあなた ほらあなたの
You inside me, look, you are...
中の私の存在は まだまだ大きくないことも 分かってるけれど
...inside me, my presence isn't very big yet, even though I know that,
今この同じ 瞬間共有してる 実感
The real feeling of sharing this exact moment right now,
塵も積もれば山と撫子 略して塵積も山と撫子
Dust piled up becomes a nadeshiko mountain, or in short, a piled-dust nadeshiko mountain.
クラクラリ クラクラル あなたを見つけたら それだけで眩しすぎて
Dizzy and dizzy, whenever I spot you, just that is so dazzling
クラクラル クラクラリ あなたを思っている それだけで溶けてしまう
Dizzy and dizzy, just thinking about you makes me melt away.
神様ありがとう 運命のいたずらでも
Thank you, God, even if this is fate's mischief,
巡り逢えたことが 幸せなの
Being able to cross paths with you is such happiness.
恋する気持ち 乙女はロックパーティ ザ・クリエイション
A maiden's loving feeling is a rock party creation
ふわふわり ふわふわル あなたが名前を呼ぶ それだけで宙へ浮かぶ
Fluffy and light, fluffy and airy, just you calling my name makes me float into the sky.
ふわふわル ふわふわり あなたが笑っている それだけで笑顔になる
Fluffy and airy, fluffy and light, just you smiling makes me smile too.
神様ありがとう 運命のいたずらでも
Thank you, God, even if this is fate's mischief,
巡り逢えたことが 幸せなの
Being able to cross paths with you is such happiness.
でもそんなんじゃだめ もうそんなんじゃほら 心は進化するよ もっともっと
But that's no good, hey, if it's like that, my heart evolves more and more.
そうそんなんじゃやだ ねえそんなんじゃまだ 私のこと見ててね ずっとずっと
Yeah, I hate that, hey, if it's like that, still look at me, always and forever.
逆光のフリューゲル
[Title: Gyakkou no Flügel]
聞こえますか…？激情奏でるミュージック
Can you hear it...? Music playing passion
天に解き放て
Release it to the heavens!
聴こえますか…?!イノチ始まる脈動
Can you hear it...?! The pulsation where life begins
愛を突き上げて 遥かな星が
Thrusting love upward, distant stars
音楽となった…彼の日の風が
became music... the wind of that day
髪を揺らう瞬間 君と僕は
at the moment it shakes your hair, you and I
コドウを歌にした そして夢は
turned our heartbeats into song, and then dreams
開くよ 見たことない 世界の果てへ…
will open up, to the edge of an unseen world...
Yes, just believe
神様も知らない 光で歴史を創ろう
Let's create history with a light unknown even to God
逆光のシャワー 磨い照らす
A shower of backlight shines polished
一緒に飛ばないか Just feeling
Won't you fly with me? Just feeling
涙で濡れた羽根 重くて羽ばたけない日は
On days when wings wet with tears are too heavy to flap,
Wish その右手に添えよう
Wish, let's join our right hands
僕のチカラも 二人手なら 翼になれる Singing heart
My power too, if hand in hand, we can become wings, Singing heart
いつの日か解かる時が来るから ずっと…忘れない
The time will come when you understand someday, so I will never forget...
その時には心のあるがままに 笑顔…
At that time, let your heart be as it is, with a smile...
笑顔…忘れない
Never forget your smile...
きっと僕と君は
Surely, you and I
一羽の鳥のように
Like a single bird,
遠い手と手繋ぎ大空を
Connecting distant hands and soaring through the sky
強く羽ばたいていたんだ
With such fierce wings
そして生きる今を見た事ない明日の先へ
And now, living in this present, heading beyond an unseen tomorrow...
Yes, just believe 1000年後の今日も生まれ変わって歌いたい
Yes, just believe, 1,000 years from today, reborn, I want to sing!
暖かいよこのぬくもり
It's so warm, this warmth.
絶対離さない
I will never let go.
Just feeling 運命なんてない
Just feeling, there's no such thing as fate—
物語は自分にあるじゃん
The story is up to you!
逃げ出したくなったら
If you ever want to run away,
空を見上げよう勇気こそが
Look up at the sky; courage is what
輝くんだよ Singing star
Shines brightly, singing star!
遥か昔星が音楽となったあの日のたぶん僕らは
Long ago, when stars became music on that day, perhaps we...
君と出逢い神話の一つように
Met you, weaving together like a myth,
神話の一つように紡いだ
Weaving together like a myth,
何も怖くないよ
You don't have to be afraid of anything.
見た事ない世界の果てへ
To the edge of an unseen world...
Yes, just believe
神様も知らない光で歴史を創ろう
Let's create history with a light even gods don't know—
逆子のシャワー未来照らす一緒に飛ばないか
Shower of inverse light illuminating the future, won't you fly with me?
Just feeling 涙で濡れた羽
Just feeling, wings soaked with tears
重くて羽ばたけない日はwish
On days too heavy to fly, I wish...
旋律は溶け合ってシンフォニーへと二人でなら翼になれる
Melodies melt together into a symphony, together we can become wings!
Singing heart もっと高く太陽よりも高く
Singing heart, higher, higher than the sun!
UNHAPPY?
めんどい人の子
Troublesome child of man,
UNLUCKY?
生きているだけ
Just being alive,
目を逸らした過去も
Even the past I averted my eyes from,
退屈な未来も
And the tedious future too.
カウンセリング やれやれ
Counseling, good grief,
ここんとこずっしり ピースピース
Lately it's been so heavy, peace peace!
ねえねえねえねえ なんなくどうして 戦ってるようなそんな気がするの
Hey, hey, hey, hey, why does it feel like we're constantly fighting?
触れない 触れたくない
Untouchable, don't want to touch it.
過去の自分ととうに死んでる透明な亡霊と対決
Confronting my past self and a long-dead, transparent ghost.
一体全体 一体一秒前の奥
Deep in the memories of a painful second ago,
残念もう居ないのに
Sadly, they're not even here anymore.
あれっそ 違い アイロニーね
Wait, is that right? Oh, what irony.
透かされているのは現在の自分
What's being seen through is my present self.
ナンセンス
Nonsense!
消えないレターデ
An indelible letter,
弱音コンプレックス
Weakness complex,
取り憑かれてるみたい 巻き付いたまままだ離れない
Like being possessed, wrapped around me and still won't let go.
惜しむ日の自分 UNDEAD
The self of that regretful day, UNDEAD!
死んじゃいない お前とお前の連鎖 生きていることは
We're not dead! The chain of you and you, to live
変わり続けることだ
Is to keep changing!
不幸に甘んじて 満足するなよ 幸せになろうとしないなんて嘘だ
Don't settle for misfortune and be satisfied; saying you don't want to be happy is a lie!
この世 この世は 一期一会ファタジィ
This world, this world is a once-in-a-lifetime fantasy,
次は鬼が出るか蛇が出るか 出会って逢ってやっと始まる物語
Next will an ogre appear or a snake? A story that finally begins when we meet!
さあ人か化け物が
Now, are you human or a monster?
謳う代ピーピース
Singing loud, peace peace!
といんなんとかどうして 未来になんぞなんの
Hey, why on earth do we care about the future?
希望もない期待できないような気がして
Feeling like there's no hope, no expectations.
もう随分生きている 既視感とテンプレで食傷
Having lived for quite long, jaded by déjà vu and templates.
素敵な出来事の気配もない 残念
There's not even a hint of wonderful events, unfortunately.
積んだ経験の因果 形骸化された神話 退屈な進化
The karma of accumulated experience, ossified myths, boring evolution—
要は刺激が欲しいんだ 飽きちゃった慣れちゃった
The point is I want stimulation, got bored, got used to it!
なんて 整っていくガイダンス 増えるコンプライアンス
What a neat and orderly guidance, increasing compliance!
蓋を開けてくみたい
Like opening the lid,
吸い尽くして
sucking it all dry,
どれもこれもどれも
each and every one of them
同じ味がする
tastes exactly the same.
アンデッド 死んじゃいない
Undead, you're not dead.
お前とお前の連鎖
The chain linking you and me.
何時の世も 過去も 未来も 今にあるんだ
No matter the era, past and future exist right now.
生きてることを 屈辱に果たすよ
Fulfilling life as a humiliation.
目指せ ハッピーエンド
Aim for a happy ending!
アンデッド 死んじゃいない
Undead, you're not dead.
お前に言っているんだ
I'm talking right to you.
幸せを諦めてしまうな
Don't give up on happiness.
独り取り残され ただ苦しみに慣れて 耐えているだけじゃ
Being left behind, just getting used to suffering and enduring it,
死んでるも当然 しかばねのアンデッド
being dead is only natural—a corpse's undead.
アンハッピー？
Unhappy?
禍の主よ 卑下ならざる者も
Lord of misfortune, even those who aren't self-deprecating,
絶えず目指せよ
constantly aim for it!
生きてるなら 不幸に浸るも 幸せになるのも
If you're alive, whether drowning in misery or finding happiness,
そう全部全部お前だ
yes, it's all, all up to you.
Past & Future Can't change the Past
Past & Future Run for the Future
人知れず眠る心
A heart sleeping in secret,
生き抜けこの化け物ばかりの物語
survive this story full of monsters!
物語
A story.
Stop, listen, rewind
Come a little closer
Listen to the silence beating hard wherever you go
Fast forward in time
Time is moving in deeper
All deeper and deeper into you, there is no way out
It must have been the time when I lost my way
Through the chaos of time it was stormy
Spinning out of it all, You left me in life of confusion
Spinning out of it all, you left me in a life of confusion.
Take a time to remember when I met you
Take time to remember when I met you,
See the truth beneath all the lies and hate
Nothing wrong being scared, We're all the same tomorrow
Hear what I'm saying, Rewind our vision
I want to hold you, Please take a moment now
Let me into your heart, Rewind your vision
Don't let it hold you back and today
Just explore, We can fall in love, You know the truth is there
Let me know why, Between us, now
Stop my tears rewind, Overlapping blue shadows
Touching in the darkness far away, wishing it was real
Stay with me tonight, I don't want this sadness
Sadness overflowing in my mind, I wanna hold on
Hear what I'm saying, Rewind our vision
I want your heartbeat, I want you wanting me
Let me into your heart, Rewind your vision
I can't remember days without you, Take my hand
We can fall in love, You know the truth is there
Let me know why, Between us, love
Rewind our vision
I want to hold you
Please take a moment now
Let me into your heart
Rewind your vision
Don't let it hold you back into day
Just explore, we can fall in love
You know the truth is there
Let me know why
Between us love
いつも通りのある日のこと 君は突然立ち上がり言った
Just like any other day, you suddenly stood up and said,
今夜、星を見に行こう
"Let's go stargazing tonight."
君の知らない物語 作詞・作曲：ryo (supercell)
[Song: Kimi no Shiranai Monogatari - Lyrics & Music: ryo (supercell)]
たまにはいいこと言うんだね
"You occasionally say nice things."
なんてみんなして言って笑った
Everyone laughed, saying that.
あかりもない道を進む
Walking down a path without any lights,
バカみたいにはしゃいでは歩いた
we walked around acting like fools.
抱え込んだ孤独や不安に押し潰されないように
So as not to be crushed by the loneliness and anxiety we harbored,
真っ暗な世界から見上げた夜空は星が降るようで
the night sky we looked up at from the pitch-black world seemed to be raining stars.
いつか話そう
"Someday I'll tell you..."
君のことを追いかける私がいた
about the me who was chasing after you.
だけどどこだろう 一番星様
But where could you be, evening star?
どうかお願い 驚かないで聞いてよ
Please, I beg you, don't be surprised and listen.
私のこの想いを
This feeling of mine...
あれがデネブ、アルタイル、ベガ 君は指さす夏の三角形
That's Deneb, Altair, Vega—you point to the Summer Triangle.
覚えて空を見上げる
Remembering that, I look up at the sky.
やっと見つけた織姫様 だけどどこだろう彦星様
I finally found Orihime, but where is Hikoboshi?
これじゃひとりぼっちだ
At this rate, I'm all alone.
楽しげなひとつ隣の君を 私は何も言えず見つめていた
I could say nothing as I gazed at you, happily sitting right beside me.
結末は…
The ending...
何も言えなくて 恋とは違う
couldn't be said. It's not love—
君の事をどこかで分かっていた
I knew somewhere deep down about you.
見つめ合ってだって 届きやしない
Even if we look at each other, it won't reach you.
駄目だよ 泣かないで そう言い聞かせた
"It's no good, don't cry," I told myself.
強がる私は臆病で 興味がないようなふりをしてた
The acting-tough me was cowardly, pretending to have no interest.
だけど…
But...
胸を刺す痛いは増してく ああ、好きになるってこういうことなんだね
The pain piercing my chest increases. Ah, so this is what it means to fall in love.
こんな日々は永遠じゃない
This time will not last forever,
だけどあの日々はビューティフル
yet those days are so beautiful.
君の瞳 手 そして温かい笑顔
Your eyes, your hands, and your warm smile
それは私の宝物
are my treasure.
言えなかった 言えなかった
I couldn't say it, I couldn't say it,
二度と もう戻れない
we can never return again
あの夏の日の きらめく星
to that summer day's twinkling stars.
今 手を思い出せるよ
Now I can remember your hands,
笑った顔も 怒った顔も
your laughing face and angry face.
大好きでした おかしいよね
I loved you so much, it's funny, right?
分かってたのに 君の知らない
Even though I knew, it's a secret
私だけの秘密
that only I know.
夜を超えて 遠い思い出の
Crossing the night, to distant memories,
君が 指をさす
you point your finger.
無邪気な声で
With an innocent voice,
I know this will not remain forever
However it's beautiful
Your eyes, hands and your warm smile, they're my treasure
It's hard to forget
I wish there was a solution, don't spend your time in confusion
I'll turn back now and spread my broken wings
Still strong enough to cross the ocean with my broken wings
How far should I go drifting in the wind
Higher and higher in the light
Still strong enough to cross the ocean with my broken wings
How far should I go drifting in the wind
Across the sky, just keep on flying
計測のできない痛みと 計測のできない時間の流れが
With an unmeasurable pain and an unmeasurable flow of time,
すべてを埋めてしまおうとしても
even if I try to fill everything up,
それでも私には感じられる
still, I can feel it.
空から落ちてくるのは 雨ではなくて…
What falls from the sky is not rain...
Did I ever chain you down to my heart
'Cause I was afraid of you
No, I couldn't hold any longer, love is not a toy
Let go of me now
The time we spent is perpetual, our future is not real
So I'll leap into the air with broken wings
still strong enough to cross the ocean with
my broken wings
How far should I go drifting in the wind
Higher and higher in the light
still strong enough to cross the ocean with
my broken wings
How far should I go drifting in the wind
Across the sky, just keep on flying
空から落ちてくるのは あれは雨ではなくて...
What falls from the sky... is not rain...
認めていた臆病な過去
I admitted my cowardly past,
わからないままで怯えてた
frightened and not knowing why,
後ろの自分が現実を今に映す
as my past self mirrors today's reality.
怖がってた後ろの自分が
The timid self I was afraid of
現実を今に映す
now reflects reality into the present.
歪むいつもの空を描いた
I drew the usual distorted sky,
ここはきっと 儚い心見出して
finding a fleeting heart right here.
夢で高く飛んだ体は
My body, soaring high in dreams,
どんな不安まとっても振り払っていく
brushes aside any anxiety it wears.
眠る小さな思い広がり出して
My slumbering little feelings start to spread,
気付く 弱い私 君がいれば
realizing that if you are here with my weak self,
暗い世界 強く入れた
I could enter this dark world with strength.
長い夢見る 心は永遠で
My heart, dreaming a long dream, is forever.
I wanna always be with you, I'll give you everything I have
探してた 導く光 触れれば
If I touch the guiding light I was searching for,
すべて思い出して 駆け抜けてく
remembering everything, running through
大切な今を 暮れる小さな
this precious present, the small, dim
目を落とし 世界を知った それはいつも
world where I closed my eyes and learned the truth—it was always so warm,
温かいのに痛くて 繋ぐ確かから
yet painful to want it so much...
願いが重なり合って 見える迷いは
If wishes overlap and the hesitation I can see
動き始めた 君がいれば
starts to move, with you here,
暗い世界 強く入れた
I could enter the dark world with strength.
深い眠りの中 淀んだよた
Floating within a deep slumber,
変わらない約束だった
it was an unchanging promise.
二人信じた 絆はそう 生命に
The bond we both believed in became our very life.
声が届くまで 名前を呼んで
Call out my name until your voice reaches me!
出会えた奇跡 感じたいもっと
I want to feel the miracle of meeting you even more!
夢で高く飛んだ体はどんな不安まとっても振り払っていく
My body, soaring high in dreams, brushes aside any anxiety it wears.
眠る小さな思い広がり出して
My slumbering little feelings start to spread,
気付く 弱い私 君がいれば
realizing that if you are here with my weak self,
暗い世界 強く入れた
I could enter this dark world with strength.
長い夢見る 心は永遠で
My heart, dreaming a long dream, is forever.
I wanna always be with you
I wanna hold you tight right now
I swear that I will wipe your tears
I'll give you everything I have
世界で一番おひめさま　そうゆう扱い心得てよ
I'm the princess of this world, so treat me accordingly.
その一　いつもと違う髪型に気がつくこと
First: Notice when my hairstyle is different than usual.
その二　ちゃんと靴までみること　いいね？
Second: Look all the way down at my shoes, okay?
その三　私の一言には三つの言葉で返事すること
Third: Answer every word I say with three words.
わかったら右手がお留守なnosisなにをなんとかして！
If you understand, do something about my idle right hand!
別にわがままなんて言ってないんだから　キミに心から思ってほしいの　かわいいって
It's not like I'm being selfish. I want you to truly think I'm cute.
キミに　心から　思ってほしいの　かわいいって
I want you from the bottom of your heart to think I'm cute.
世界で一番おひめさま　気がついてねえねえ　待たせるなんて論外よ
I'm the princess of this world. Notice me, hey, making me wait is out of the question!
あたしを誰だと思ってるの　もうなんだか　甘いものが食べたい！
Who do you think I am? Suddenly, I want something sweet to eat!
今すぐによっ
Right now!
欠点なんてかわいいの間違いでしょ　ボクはよろしくせっの
Faults are just mistakes for cute, right? I'll say "Nice to meet you" ready, set—
あのね私の話ちゃんと聞いて　ちょっと！
Hey, listen properly to what I have to say, wait!
あ、それとね白いお馬さん決まってるでしょ　迎えに来て
Oh, and you've decided on the white horse, right? Come pick me up.
わかったら貸し切って手をつないでおひめさまして
If you understand, charter it, hold my hands, and treat me like a princess!
別にわがままなんて言ってないんだから　でもね、少し気にしてくれてもいいのよ？
It's not like I'm being selfish, but you know, it'd be nice if you cared just a little bit, right?
世界で一番私だけのおじさま　気がついてほらほら　おててが空いてますよ
The one and only mister in the world just for me. Notice me, look, my hands are free!
無口でぶあいそなそんなおじさま　もうどうして
Such a quiet, aloof mister, why...
気がついてよ早く　絶対！
Notice me quickly, absolutely!
キミはわかってない　わかってないわ
You don't understand, you really don't understand!
いちごののったショートケーキ
Strawberry shortcake
こだわりたまごのとろけるプリン
Specialty egg melting pudding
みんなに自慢します
I'll brag to everyone
わがままだなんて思わないで　私だってやればできるもん　あとで後悔するわよ！
Don't think I'm being selfish! I can do it if I try, you'll regret it later!
世界で一番おひめさま　ちゃんとみててよね　どこかに行っちゃうよ
The princess of this world, watch me properly or I'll go somewhere else!
ほいなに抱きしめられた急にそんなの　聞かされる　危ないよ
Suddenly being hugged like that, hearing something like that, it's dangerous!
こっちのが危ないわよ
This side is even more dangerous!
はーい、ということでみなさん、獅白ボタン生誕祭2026ストレイヤーズステイにお越しくださりありがとうございます！
Alright, everyone! Thank you so much for coming to Shishiro Botan's Birthday Festival 2026 "Strayers Stay"!
ということでララライ４獅白ボタンです。配信のハッシュタグ改めて、右上に…どっちだ？どっちか、よろしくお願いします、こっちです。
So I'm Shishiro Botan of LALALION. To reiterate the stream hashtag, it's in the top right... Which side? Whichever side, please use it, it's this way.
獅白ボタン生誕祭2026たくさんつぶやいてください！私もチェックしますんでよろしくお願いします！
Please tweet a lot with the Shishiro Botan Birthday hashtag! I'll be checking them too, so please look forward to it!
ということで
So, with that said...
早速なんですけど
this is a bit sudden, but
次のパートの、まぁ次
for the next part of the show...
の次かな、ちょっといろいろあるんですけど
well, there's a lot going on, but
まぁ次のパートのゲストをお呼びして一緒にちょっとMCやっていきたいと思います！
we'll invite our guests for the next part and do the MC together!
ということで、来いよ！いつもメンバーたちよ！
So, come on out, our usual members!
来たぜ！いつものいつもの
Here they come, our usual...
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much.
いつものメンバーたちということでじゃあちょっと改めて自己紹介してもらおうかな。
Our usual members, so let's have them introduce themselves again.
じゃあもう、はい！ネネから！はい！
Then, Nene-chi, please!
はい！
Yes!
はい、ねぽらぼのね桃鈴ねねです。よろしくお願いします！
NEPOLABO's Momosuzu Nene-ne! Nice to meet you!
おそろしく早い
So fresh!
次！
Next!
はい、次！ねぽらぼのぽ、おまるポルカです。よろしくお願いします！
NEPOLABO's Omaru Polka! Nice to meet you!
よろしくお願いします！
Thank you very much!
次、ラ！
Next, Lamy!
はい、ねぽらぼのら、ぽろライブごきげんがおかんぞう雪花ラミィです。よろしくお願いします！
NEPOLABO's Yukihana Lamy! Nice to meet you!
ということでお馴染みのメンツ揃いました。
So, we've got our familiar lineup.
ししろん！
Botan-san!
ダンス始まっちゃいましたけど
The dancing has already started, but...
これど、どうですか？
how is it?
いや、なんかの顔を見ると安心するね。
Seeing your first face is reassuring!
よかった、よかった。いやあ、来年もよろしくお願いします。
Good, good! Yeah, we're looking forward to next year too!
見せちゃう、そういうとこみたいな。
It's like... look at her cute side!
ステージね、かっこいいよね。
The venue looks so cool!
すごい、ほら。あ、ネオン管もある。
So many lights, and...
ちょっとネオンピカピカしてますけど。
The neon is sparkling!
好きだよね。やっぱ好きなの結構、あの、めちゃ食べる方だからさ。
You like that, right? I love it too.
こういうのもめちゃ使っちゃうよね。
You end up using stuff like this a lot, huh?
そう、あの近未来的な。
So future-like!
そうなんすよ。
That's right.
ちなみに、コンセプトとかあるんですか？
By the way, is there a concept for this?
今回結構、アニメの曲とかもたくさん歌わせてもらってて。
This time, we got to sing lots of anime songs,
プラスなんか私の好きなその、EDMというかサイバー感が好きなので、ちょっと合体した感じかな？
plus my favorite EDM, or rather, cyber style.
ハマってる？ハマってる感じ？
Does it match?
うん、ちょっとドパッてる感じ。
It totally matches!
ドパッてる感じ？
Does it?
ということでね、ここまでを、まあいろいろ振り返ってもみようかなとも思ったんですけど
So, we thought we'd look back on everything up to this point,
どうしようかな？
how should we do it?
なんか私、今日1曲目にさ、恋愛サーキュレーション歌ったんですよ。
Today I sang "Ren'ai Circulation" as my first song!
かわいいかったよ。
You were so cute!
可愛かったか？
Was I?
ちょっと久しぶりに、なんか可愛いのごちそうちゃったなって思って。
It's been a while since I showed that cute side of me, so...
テレテレ、テレッテやって、テレテレ、テレッテやって、テッテテレッテってやって。
Terering! We should do the Terering!
可愛いだろ！可愛い！ダンス！
It was so cute!
テレテレ、テレテレ、ヨンチャイが出てたよ。
The four of us were doing it.
今回で何ちゃいになった？
How many chai was it this time?
今回でも4ちゃいから次の、フリュージュエル、そらちゃんがちゃんと歌ったときにももう20歳ぐらいになった。
This time, from 4-chai, next when Sora-chan sang "Blueger," she was already around 20-chai.
飛んだ！かっこいい！
So fast!
飛んだから。
She flew, so...
いろいろちょっと、MCがてら紹介したいことがあって。
I have some things I want to introduce as MC,
ちょっとお手伝いしていただけたら嬉しいなと思ってます。
so I'd be happy if you could help me out!
はい！じゃあちょっと告知、はい、告知させていただきたいと思います。
Sure! Let's make the announcements.
まずは、獅白ぼたん生誕に、え、生誕記念
First is Shishiro Botan's...
2026のグッズの販売告知となります。
2026 merchandise announcement!
イラストはママ、トマリ先生に描いていただきました。ありがとうございます！
The illustration was drawn by Mama Tomari-sensei! Thank you very much!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
イラストのテーマはね、ちょっとゴシック系の獅白ぼたんに仕上げていただきました。
The theme of the illustration is finished with a gothic Shishiro Botan.
匂わせる匂わせる。
It hints at things.
いいでしょ？
Right?
じゃあ、ちょっと見ていきましょう。こちら！はい、どどん。じゃん。
Let's take a look at them one by one. Here we go, ta-da!
はい、ステッカー。
First, the sticker!
これはキービジュアルのイラストを使用した大きめサイズのステッカーです。
This is a large sticker featuring key visual art.
貼って剥がせるタイプになってるので、あの何度でもはい使えるかなと思ってます。
It's a peel-and-stick type, so you can use it multiple times!
キラキラホログラム仕様です。
It has a sparkly hologram finish.
可愛い！
Pretty!
じゃ続いてこちら。どん。
Next is this, ta-da!
はい、SSRBのエコバッグです。
The SSRB Eco Bag!
ちょっとしたお買い物にね、気軽に持ち歩けるエコバッグになってます。
An eco bag that's easy to carry for quick shopping trips.
SSRB型のポーチも付属しているので、あのその中に収納していただければね、お買い物も簡単になるかなと思います。安い。
It comes with an SSRB pouch, so you can easily store it away!
安い。
Cheap!
続いてこちら。でざ。
And next, this!
コンテナBOX。
The Container Box!
リバイバルじゃない？
Revival! Revival!
リバイバルなんだけどね、デザインは変わってます。
It's a revival, but the design has changed.
SSRBデザインのコンテナボックスになってて、折りたためる仕様になってます。
It's a foldable container box featuring the SSRB design.
これめちゃめちゃ人気だったもんね。
This was super popular before!
で、やっぱね、みんなグッズ増えてきていると思うんで、
And since everyone's goods are increasing,
あの、そうそうそう、収納して、していたけたら嬉しいなと思ってます。
I hope you'll use it for storage!
すごい。
Amazing.
はい、続いてこちら。SSRBのティッシュカバーです。
Next is this: the SSRB Tissue Cover!
ふんわり質感のね、SSRBモチーフのティッシュカバーになってるので、
It's an SSRB-motif tissue cover with a fluffy texture,
いつでも手元に置いてね、鼻かんだり涙拭いたりしてくれようなふわふわ仕様。
so you can keep it close by to blow your nose or wipe your tears!
ふわふわ仕様。
Fluffy!
そしてフルセット購入特典あります！
And we have a full set purchase bonus!
直筆サインと、複製メッセージ入りのポストカードです。
It's a postcard with a handwritten signature and a printed message!
イラストがもうママのイラストが最高なんで、
Mama's illustration is the absolute best!
是非フルセットね、購入していただけたら嬉しいなと。フルだよね、フルセット。
I'd be so happy if you bought the full set!
そして2つ目のお知らせ、こちら！はい。
And our second announcement is this!
なんだ？な、なんと！
What could it be?
獅白ぼたんの新曲『STRAY & STAY』この後24時、9月20日日曜日の0時からデジタルリリースされます！
Shishiro Botan's new original song "STRAY & STAY" will be digitally released starting midnight on Sunday, September 20th!
今回はね、あの『ヒミレクル』作ってくれたしいなのりりん先生が作ってくれたんですよ、また。ありがとうございます！
This time, Shiina Rurii-sensei, who created "Himiwaku," made it for us again. Thank you very much!
何かずっと…味気する…
Like, it has this lingering taste...
ずっとリピートしてもらえると、
if you keep on repeating it,
なんかどんどん、どんどん、なんか…
it just keeps getting more and more...
噛めば噛むほど
The more you chew,
ドパドパしていくんじゃないかなと。
the more dopamine rushes out.
はい、よろしくお願いします。
Yes, please look forward to it.
この配信が終わったあとMV公開されますので、
The MV will be released after this stream,
ぜひお楽しみに！
so please look forward to it!
新曲ちなみになんとこのあと披露しますので、
And we'll perform the new song right after this,
絶対聴いてください！
so be sure to listen!
はい、聞いてください！そして、3つ目の告知、
Yes, please listen! And there's a third announcement.
こ、こちら！ドン！
Th-This! Ta-da!
私、獅白ぼたンのファーストアルバムが発売決定しました！
My first album has been decided for release!
おめでとうございます！ありがとうございます！
Congratulations! Thank you so much!
記念すべき、はい、ファーストアルバムということで、たっぷり10曲入ってます。
As this is our first album, it's packed with 10 songs.
今年リリースしたシンミラクルから溶け放たての4曲に加えて、新曲「Stray & Stay」ももちろん収録されてます。
In addition to the four songs released this year, the new song "Stray & Stay" is included.
さらにさらに、セキナークリエイターの皆様に書き下ろししていただいた新曲5曲入ってます！
Plus five new songs written by creators are included!
何曲なんだ一体。もうわかんない、足し算できない。
How many songs is that? I can't do addition!
ぜひよろしくお願いします。
I hope you'll check it out.
全員に直筆サイン入りのグッズも用意していますので、全員！
We've prepared autographed goods for everyone!
ぜひ詳細は公式ページをチェックしていただけたら嬉しいです。
Please check the official page for details.
本当にありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
このアルバムはですね、ホロライブ公式オンラインショップでこのあと予約開始となります。
This album will be available for pre-order on the Hololive online shop.
たくさんの人に手に取ってもらえると嬉しいです。よろしくおねがいします！
I'd be happy if many people pick it up.
ラストのこのお知らせ結構重大発表なので、こちらご覧くださーい！どん！
The final announcement is a major one, so take a look!
緊急告知！！獅白ぼたん特殊なオフイベ開催決定！
Emergency Announcement!! Shishiro Botan special offline event decided!
2027年2月末〜3月中旬あけておいてね！長くない？長すぎる！
Keep late February to mid-March 2027 open!
※1日じゃないよ！
It's not just one day!
ということで皆さん、ぜひ楽しみにしといてもらえたら嬉しいなと思ってます。
So I hope you'll look forward to it.
ネポラボの、ネポラボの皆さんもうずっとね、来てほしいなと思いつつ
I've been wanting Nepolabo to come too,
いいの？いいの？なんか、まだ内緒だけどね。
Is that okay? Well, it's still a secret though.
めっちゃ楽しみにしていてほしい。全力でふざけちゃうよ。ふざけてほしい、期待して。
I want you to really look forward to it. We're going all out and goofing off.
ま、2月末から3月中旬予定になっておりますので、情報解禁またしていくので、チェックよろしくお願いします。
It's scheduled from late February to mid-March, please check it out.
以上、獅白ぼたん、誕生日記念2026のグッズ情報、アルバムリリース情報、新曲情報、そして重大発表おしらせでした！
And that concludes the merch, album, new song info, and major announcement!
ライブもね、ちょっと終盤戦ということで、ネポラボの皆さんも、この後一緒に歌わせていただきますので！
The live is entering its final stage, and Nepolabo will sing with me too.
あと、メン限アンコールライブもね、今日ありますので、ぜひそちらも来ていただけたら嬉しいです。
There's a member-limited encore live today too, please come!
じゃあ私ちょっと次の曲に着替えるんで、じゃあみんなちょっと繋いでおいてもらっていいかな？
I'll go change for the next song, so keep things going!
ネポラボのみんなもね、ちょっと準備して、準備してね。ありがとうございましたー！またね！バイバーイ！
Nepolabo members, get ready too. Thank you very much! Bye-bye!
ネポラボともこのあと歌うんですが、まずは次の曲、私の新曲を聞いていただきたいなと思いますので、聞いてください。「Stray & Stay」。
We'll sing with Nepolabo too, but first, please listen to my new song, "Stray & Stay."
♪
[Music]
Losing the faint light,
形のない、夜に滲む 感覚の様、
Like a formless sensation bleeding into the night,
不安定な位相が 走る思考、
Unstable phases and racing thoughts,
鼓動打つ気をもたげ Note 同じ軌道を
Heart pounding, raising my spirit, following the same orbit,
描くように綺麗に散らばった
scattering cleanly,
Sway, Sway, Sway, in my own place.
Sway, Without a trace.
ぐちゃぐちゃになった言葉が、消えてしまう前に、
Before my jumbled words fade away,
掴みたいと願った、
I wished to hold on to it,
ただ繰り返した、ただ繰り返した、ただ繰り返した、
Repeating it over and over again,
ただ繰り返した、また繰り返して、また繰り返して、また繰り返して、
repeating it again and again...
まだ、届かないでいて。
Stay out of reach just a little longer.
Waking from a shallow sleep, Mm...
形のない、夜に滲む 感覚の様、
Like a formless sensation bleeding into the night,
呼吸、
breathing,
未完成な鼓動、またもや轟く、
an incomplete pulse roaring once again,
同じ過去を辿る荒涼に吸い切れる透明なもの
a transparent thing sucked into the desolation of the same past—
Sway, Sway, Sway, we are free.
Sway, Fading away.
ぐちゃぐちゃになった言葉が、色褪せる前に、
Before my jumbled words lose their color,
書き留めたいと 思った、
I wanted to write it down,
ただ繰り返した、また繰り返して、
Repeating it endlessly, repeating it again and again...
まだ、忘れないでいて。
Don't forget it just yet.
共に限界までバーニクロス滑り出せ
Slide out together to the limit, Burning Cross!
Are you ready? Fight!
Lala... Rurila...
何度這いずり泥を噛んだって
No matter how many times I crawled and bit the mud,
先競い合い背中を託す 戦場に咲く友がいる
competing ahead, trusting each other's backs, there are friends blooming on the battlefield!
ガチンコでシャッフルな時も 何故か形迎える
Even during serious, shuffled times, why do we embrace shape?
スフォルツァンドの限界値まで フォルテロ銀河に溺れよう
Let's drown in the Fortissimo galaxy up to the Sforzando limit!
ブルル、ブルル、ブルル、ブルル、ブルルって突き出せ
Buru, buru, push forward trembling,
奪い合っても繰り絞れ
even if we fight over it, squeeze it out,
人が作る想いの答えを信じよう
let's believe in the answer of feelings created by people!
ハートを震わせて相手殴れ
Shake your heart and strike your opponent,
100度負けても101度目に立てるから
because even if you lose 100 times, you can stand up on the 101st!
この力とは みんなが紡いだ この歌の響きだ
This power is the echo of this song woven by everyone!
交わる勇気託し合って Never give up!
Entrusting each other with the courage to intersect, Never give up!
さあ夜明けへと
Now, toward the dawn,
怖さも弱さも涙も ちぎって分け合い
tearing apart and sharing fear, weakness, and tears,
勝利を掴め！
seize victory!
握れば握るほどまた開く意味を知り
The more you grip, the more you learn the meaning of opening your hand,
相手の傷が伝わり 無刀の極み憧れる
feeling the opponent's wounds, yearning for the pinnacle of swordsmanship without a blade,
因縁の連鎖にこそ 撃鉄を起こせ...
trigger the hammer precisely within the chain of fate...
因縁の連鎖にこそ 撃鉄を起こせ…！
Pull the trigger on this chain of fate...!
レクイエムじゃない 歌で逢えたら？
What if we met through song, not a requiem?
オレの知らない 温もりが 誰かの想い出の中
Warmth I never knew, inside someone's memories...
生きてるのだとしたら？
If that means it's alive,
完全否定以外にも 違う道があるんだと
then there must be another path besides total denial.
だから絶対 この手と 不器用なこの手は
So absolutely, this hand and this clumsy hand
差し伸べる祈りを 忘れはしない
will never forget the prayer they extend.
だから戦え 痛みを抱き 分かり合える
So fight, embrace the pain, and understand each other!
そうぶち込め みんなが
Drive it in, everyone's
作った歌の願いが 重なる勇気
song wishes become overlapping courage,
許す勇気
courage to forgive!
さあ 全てのセカイが
Now, let all worlds—
善も悪もごった煮の 世界を愛せ
where good and evil are mixed together—love the world!
世界を愛せ！
Love the world!
大好きな歌の中なら 声にしてもいいのかな
If it's inside my favorite song, is it okay to voice it?
想い出が強さになった 君ならば歌えるはず
Memories have turned into strength; surely you can sing it.
傷という過去が生まれて 未来へはどう描くんだ？
A past called scars is born, how will you draw the future?
心から オレは 「ありがとう」を 歌ってあげたいんだ
From the bottom of my heart, I want to sing "Thank you" to you!
100度負けても 101度目に立てる
Even if you lose a hundred times, you can stand on the 101st.
と笑う この力とは みんなで
And smile! What is this power? Together,
繋いだ ものの 響きだ！ 交わる勇気
it's the resonance of things we connected! Courage to cross paths,
託し合えて
entrusting each other,
さあ 夜明けの 始まりを吠え 歌え
Now howl and sing the start of dawn,
CROSS BRAVERS 勝利を掴め！
X-BRAVERS, seize victory!